{
  "reference_number": "2020",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Carbon Dioxide - Reducing net carbon dioxide emissions to zero by 2050",
      "answer_index": 13,
      "notes": "Earlier would be better"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": "Overseas carbon credits can and are being gamed. They invite dishonesty."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "As you will see in submissions at the end, we can very easily achieve zero net carbon. It just demands some courage and imagination\n from the government"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": "Only if they are being revised downward"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Again, only if they are being revised downward"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Go for the low hanging fruit first to achieve the fastest results possible and to encourage everyone that we are succeeding. The\nharder ones can be worked on in the mean time. Government sometimes has to actually do things but at it's best, it sets the playing\n\nfield so that we do the necessary. This greatly multiplies her effectiveness. Keep this in mind when making legislation."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Advising the Government on policy settings in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 6,
      "notes": "Also publicizes her recommendations and reports how well the government is responding to these suggestions"
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "We have very little choice, unfortunately. We (humans) are very unlikely to achieve the world goal for carbon reduction and are likely to\n\nface some pretty serious consequence. For instance, we should be retreating from flood areas both by rivers and by the sea. We\nneed a way of spreading the pain over the longest period possible so that we are not hit by sudden \"Christchurches\". For instance\nwe could have a policy that the government has an open offer to buy up any dwellings in flood prone areas for the government\n\nvaluation plus 10%. Anyone can take up the offer at any time."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "The more interaction and discussion and transparency the more likely we are to succeed"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "I have been writing on zero emissions on my blog for some years. Below I submit the URL's with a short comment for each one. As I\n\nsaid above, the government sometimes actually has to do things itself but at it's best, it sets the playing field; the rules, so that we do\nthe necessary. These article are very much predicated on this principle. 1) Demand Balancing of our electrical grid Traditionally power\n\ncompanies have operated by supply balancing; bringing on new generation as the demand increases. Power companies must be\nencouraged to use demand balancing; opening up new demand as base demand decreases. The best incentive for this is price but\n\nthe infrastructure must be in place so that you can automatically turn on various devices (such as car charging) as the price\ndecreases. http://mtkass.blogspot.com/2018/04/electrical-demand-balancing.html 2) Election financing The one ring that controls\nthem all is election financing. Who Pays the Piper Calls the Tune was never so true as with election financing. Vested interest\n\nfinancing of political parties must cease completely. Otherwise we will never reach our goals of zero carbon.\nhttp://mtkass.blogspot.com/2018/01/wasted-effort.html 3) Sorting Out Dairy Farms This doesn't mean reducing our dairy herd.\n\nDairying could become the darlings of the green movement. The devil is in the detail.\nhttp://mtkass.blogspot.com/2018/01/mitigating-harm-dairy-causes-to.html 4) Sorting Out Farming For most of our (human) history we\n\nhave released carbon into the atmosphere from our soils adding to atmospheric Carbon Dioxide. This carbon could be returned to\nthe soil by correct farming while at the same tome markedly improving the bottom line of the farmers both in individual crop\nproduction and reliability of crops. http://mtkass.blogspot.com/2018/01/conservation-agriculture.html 5) Our History Here is a book\n\nreview of the history of Humans destroying their soils and in doing so releasing carbon into the atmosphere. Here in New Zealand we\nare continuing this destructive tradition. http://mtkass.blogspot.com/2017/11/dirt.html 6)Composting Barns Composting barns\n\nensure that any gas that goes off manure goes off as Carbon dioxide rather than as methane. Methane is a far more potent green\nhouse gas than Carbon dioxide. There are many other benefits to the farmer. http://mtkass.blogspot.com/2017/10/composting-\n\nbarns.html 7)This is the Blockbuster David Montgomery has traveled all over the world observing farmers who have come up,\nindependently of each other, of a new/old way of farming. If adopted widely, a great deal of the carbon we have vented into the\n\natmosphere would be incorporated into the soil. This is a book review of one of his books. 8) The Ratchet Effect One of the doges\nthe power companies use to disadvantage the small solar power owner is what I call the Ratched Effect. If you want increased solar\ninstallation by private households, this must not be allowed. http://mtkass.blogspot.com/2013/10/solar-power-and-ratchet.html\n\n9)Making the Installation of Solar Electric Economically Feasible http://mtkass.blogspot.com/2013/06/net-metering.html 10) Another\none for Making Solar Electric Worthwhile http://mtkass.blogspot.com/2013/04/solar-electric-whats-missing.html 11) Charcoal Char\n\ncan be incorporated into the soil. It has no contained nutrients itself but fulfils a number of important functions in the soil besides\nsequestering carbon for a very long period (charcoal is refractory). If plantation wood was built into long lasting structures and the\n\nwaste charred and put in our soils, we would be sequestering considerable carbon from the atmosphere.\nhttp://mtkass.blogspot.com/2010/11/biochar.html 12) Mining Royalties and carbon reduction/sequestration Mining is a 'one-off'\nWhen it is done it is done and won't come again. There is no justification for using the revenue from mining (coal, gold, iron etc etc)\n\nfor current consumption. It should be put into investments for the long term. The best of these would be to encourage carbon\nreduction and sequestration for the future of our descendents. http://mtkass.blogspot.com/2010/10/mining-royalties-and-\n\nrenewable-energy.html 13) Other Benefits There are so many other benefits to taking the various measures that would address\nclimate change (zero carbon) that we could almost ignore climate change and take these measure just for their other benefits.\n\nhttp://mtkass.blogspot.com/2010/10/forget-climate-change.html 14) Wind Farms Wind farms have got a bad rap in some quarters.\nMuch of this is Nimbi'ism but some may be justified. The government should work our (research) which is which to a) put the\n\nnimbi'ism in it's place and if any concerns are justified, address them. http://mtkass.blogspot.com/2010/07/enabling-wind-farms.html\n15) Electric Cars Clearly, our main source of carbon emissions is our fleet and the domestic fleet is most easily addressed. This blog\ngives the benefits of increasing the uptake of electric cars and the ways it can be achieved.\n\nhttp://mtkass.blogspot.com/2010/07/electric-cars-in-new-zealand-uptake-of.html 16) Jim Hansen Jim Hansen has proposed a way of\nreducing carbon emissions. It is at the heart of the problem. It would compensate the public for any extra expense during the\n\ntransition (Actually the benefits both during and after the conversion to renewables are immense) Show courage and adopt his\nsuggestion. http://mtkass.blogspot.com/2009/12/jim-hansens-climate-change-solution.html 17) Legislation for Electric Cars Actually\n\nthis applies far beyond just electric cars. Government is at the best when it sets the scene and lets us get on with doing the\nnecessary. http://mtkass.blogspot.com/2009/11/legislation-for-electric-cars.html"
    }
  ]
}
